<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Precelerator English Blog</title>
    <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en" />
    <updated>2020-10-07T21:47:13+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en</id>

    <entry>
        <title>AWS Educate: Cloud-Services for Students with 100$ in free AWS credits</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/aws-educate-cloud-services-fuer-studierende-mit-free-plan-und-100dollar-startguthaben.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/aws-educate-cloud-services-fuer-studierende-mit-free-plan-und-100dollar-startguthaben.html</id>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:22:49+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/AWS-Educate-Starter-2.png" alt="" />
                    With AWS Educate, Amazon provides free cloud resources to students and faculty staff in order to learn about the AWS cloud and gain experience with AWS services. In addition to various video guides on different career paths (e.g. Machine Learning Engineer, Data Scientist, App Developer,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/AWS-Educate-Starter-2.png" alt="" />
                <p>With <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/de/education/awseducate/students/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Educate</a>, Amazon provides free cloud resources to students and faculty staff in order to learn about the AWS cloud and gain experience with AWS services. In addition to various video guides on different career paths (e.g. Machine Learning Engineer, Data Scientist, App Developer, DevOps Engineer, Cyber Security Engineer, etc.), university members also receive AWS credits that can be used for cloud services via the AWS console. For students of the Munich University of Applied Sciences, this amounts to $100 per year, which can be used as a kind of playground without having to deposit one's own credit card.</p>
<p>The AWS platform offers a variety of useful services related to hosting (websites, web apps, backends), authentication, cloud resources (computing power, storage space) and cloud infrastructure (databases, API gateways, etc.).</p>
<h4>How to obtain your AWS credits</h4>
<p>The first step is to register for AWS Educate with your HM email address. This can be done in the <a href="https://www.awseducate.com/registration" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dialog that can be found here</a>. After choosing your role ("student"), AWS Educate asks for a number of information, e.g. name, country, date of birth, email and expected end of studies.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/AWS-Educate.png" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-xs.png 300w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-sm.png 480w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-md.png 768w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-xl.png 1200w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-xxl.png 1600w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-xxxl.png 2560w"  alt="Registrierung bei AWS Educate" width="484" height="294">
<figcaption >Registrierung bei AWS Educate</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>After the registration is completed, it may take 1-2 days for your account to be enabled as AWS checks registration and student status. After that you will receive an email which should look like this:</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/AWS-Educate-Mail.png" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-xs.png 300w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-sm.png 480w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-md.png 768w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-xl.png 1200w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-xxl.png 1600w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Mail-xxxl.png 2560w"  alt="AWS Educate Mail" width="633" height="194"></figure>
<p>You can set your AWS Educate password using the link in the email. After accepting the terms of use, you will be forwarded to the AWS Console by clicking on the tab "AWS Account":</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/AWS-Educate-Starter.png" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-xs.png 300w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-sm.png 480w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-md.png 768w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-xl.png 1200w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-xxl.png 1600w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/9/responsive/AWS-Educate-Starter-xxxl.png 2560w"  alt="" width="939" height="516"></figure>
<p>Success! You've enabled your account and you can now annual Cloud Credits. It is worth to took a look at the FAQs in the Workbench, e.g. the following hints should be considered:</p>
<ul>
<li>All services are only supported in US East (N. Virginia) [us-east-1] region.</li>
<li>Remember to shut down your instances when not in use to make the best use of your credits.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Do you plan to launch your own projects on AWS and are interested in getting support and guidance? The HM maintains a close partnership with AWS through the <a href="https://sites.hm.edu/dt_lab/index.de.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Digital Transformation Lab (DTLab)</a> . The DTLab can provide you with contacts and support around AWS to help you get started!</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight ">Did you know? In cooperation with AWS, the DTLab organizes challenges every semester that allow students use the Amazon platform in order to tackle a series of societal problems. Head over to the <a href="https://hm.edu/sites/dt_lab/informationen/fuer_strudierende/dtlab_fuer_studierende.de.html">DTLab-Site</a> in order to to learn more about it.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Precelerator goes digital: This is what you can expect from the launch of the brand new offer at the HM</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/precelerator-goes-digital-launch-und-naechste-schritte.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/precelerator-goes-digital-launch-und-naechste-schritte.html</id>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:23:52+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/8/Screenshot-Website.png" alt="" />
                    <p>With the launch of the new website and this blog, the Precelerator, the new offer of the Strascheg Center for Entrepreneurship at HM digital, starts the new semester. Here you can find out for whom the new Precelerator is intended and which Precelerator offers will be available soon.</p>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/8/Screenshot-Website.png" alt="" />
                <p>With the launch of the new website and this blog, the Precelerator, the new offer of the Strascheg Center for Entrepreneurship at HM digital, starts the new semester. Here you can find out for whom the new Precelerator is intended and which Precelerator offers will be available soon.</p>

<p>Vom Antrag zum Projektstart</p>
<p>- gemeinsamer Antrag von HM und SCE im Rahmen der Ausschreibung Startup@FH</p>
<p>- Förderung durch das BMBF (Verlinkung der Pressemitteilung)</p>
<p>- Projektstart im 2. Halbjahr 2020, Launch jetzt zum Start des Wintersemesters</p>
<p>Projektvorhaben</p>
<p>Worum geht's im Precelerator/ an wen richtet er sich?</p>
<p>Der Precelerator im Kontext von Corona</p>
<p>Was bieten wir jetzt an Angeboten, wo corona-bedingt alles anders ist?</p>
<hr>
<h3>Call To Action</h3>
<div>Du bist Student/Lehrkraft/Mitarbeiter an der HM und willst Teil des entstehenden Precelerators werden? Wir freuen uns über jegliche Fragen und Anregungen.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Schreib uns eine Mail an <a href="mailto:precelerator@sce.de">precelerator@sce.de</a> und wir melden uns schnellstmöglich bei dir zurück.<a href="https://precelerator.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"></a></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Website-Builders for Landing Pages</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/tools-and-templates-fuer-landing-pages.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/tools-and-templates-fuer-landing-pages.html</id>
            <category term="Tools"/>
            <category term="No-Code"/>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:26:20+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/7/igor-miske-Px3iBXV-4TU-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    <div>No online marketing campaign gets along nowadays without landing page. Especially for smaller companies the own website is the center of the online presence, but often there is a lack of budget for a professional implementation. Fortunately, there are resources and tools that make it easy to create a landing page for your project or start-up. This blog post collected the most popular website builders, with which you can quickly and easily launch your own landing page.</div>

                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/7/igor-miske-Px3iBXV-4TU-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <div>No online marketing campaign gets along nowadays without landing page. Especially for smaller companies the own website is the center of the online presence, but often there is a lack of budget for a professional implementation. Fortunately, there are resources and tools that make it easy to create a landing page for your project or start-up. This blog post collected the most popular website builders, with which you can quickly and easily launch your own landing page.</div>

<h4>Drag&amp;Drop Website-Builder</h4>
<p>Modern website builders do not require any code at all. They allow you to click together your own pages by drag and drop without any programming. Such tools often offer ready-made templates into which users can insert their own content. Well-known players in this market are Carrd, Wix, Weebly, GoDaddy, Squarespace and Webflow, some of which will be briefly compared below:</p>
<p><a href="https://carrd.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Carrd</a>: Carrd eignet sich insbesondere für One-Pager, also Landing Pages o.ä., die nicht allzu komplex sind. Carrd setzt keinerlei Programmierkenntnisse voraus und bietet eine Vielzahl von <a href="https://carrd.co/build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Templates</a>, die als Startpunkt dienen können. Carrd bietet einen Free-Plan sowie kostengünstigen Pro-Plan.</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Pro: faires Pricing, Free-Plan zum Ausprobieren, ausgereifte Templates</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">Cons: gedacht für One-Pager (keine Blogs o.ä.), begrenzte Anpassbarkeit</p>
<p><a href="https://de.wix.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wix</a>: Oft belächelt als "McDonalds der Websitebuilder" verspricht Wix die kinderleichte Erstellung der eigenen Website. Wix richtet sich primär an Leute ohne Programmiererfahrung und abstrahiert jegliche Implementierungsdetails durch den visuellen Editor weg, sodass per Drag&amp;Drop Builder Seiten zusammengeklickt werden können. Wie bei anderen Websitebuildern häufig der Fall, lassen sich Wix-Seiten nicht als Code exportieren, sodass Besitzer von Wix-Seiten eine Subscription-Gebühr an Wix entrichten müssen, um ihre Seite weiter bearbeiten zu können. Wix bietet zahlreiche Plugins, um Seiten um Features zu erweitern und bietet Templates sowie einen eigenen Logo-Maker.</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Pros: Simpler Editor, richtet sich an Leute ohne IT-Hintergrund, leichter Einstieg</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">Cons: Abhängigkeit von Wix, nach initialer Auswahl lässt sich nur schwer zwischen Templates wechseln, nicht immer mobilfähig, SEO durchwachsen</p>
<p><a href="https://www.weebly.com/de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Weebly</a>/ <a href="https://de.godaddy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GoDaddy</a>: vergleichbar zu Wix.</p>
<p><a href="https://de.squarespace.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Squarespace</a>: Squarespace ist ein weiterer Player im Website-Builder Markt, der sich insbesondere durch seine professionellen <a href="https://de.squarespace.com/vorlagen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Templates </a>auszeichnet, die von Squarespace selbst designed werden und sich dadurch qualitativ von der Konkurrenz absetzen. Squarespace setzt auf minimalistischen, aber hochwertiges Design, jegliche Templates sind von Start an mobilfähig. Squarespace bietet ausführliche Guides und Ressourcen und bietet zusätzlich Live-Chat Support.</p>
<p class="msg--success msg">Pros: Qualitativ hochwertige Templates, Code-Export, Template-Wechsel</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">Cons: kein Free-Plan, nur "Try out"-Phase, teurer als Konkurrenz, Templates lassen sich nicht beliebig anpassen</p>
<p>Wordpress: Ursprünglich als Blogging-Plattform gestartet, betreibt Wordpress heute einen signifikanten Anteil aller Websites weltweit. Mit einer sehr bedienerfreundlichen Inhaltserstellung und einem umfangreichen Plugin-Systemen hat Wordpress eine geringe Einstiegsschwelle, aber trotzdem zahllose Anpassungsmöglichkeiten. Wordpress besitzt eine Vielzahl an vorgefertigten kostenlosen sowie bezahlpflichtigen Themes sowie denvon vielen geschätzte Page-Builder <a href="https://elementor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elementor</a>. Einziger Kritikpunkt sind Geschwindigkeit (abhängig von Hosting und Anzahl der Plugins oft träge) und Sicherheitslücken durch veraltete oder laienhaft umgesetzte Plugins.</p>
<p class="msg--success msg">Pros: Weit verbreitet, große Community, viele mächtige Templates</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">Cons: z.T. langsam, Plugins müssen geupdated werden</p>
<p><a href="https://webflow.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Webflow</a>: Betitelt sich selbst als "Design Tool of the future" und bietet dementsprechend enorm umfangreiche Konfigurations- und Designanpassungen. Ebenfalls ein browserbasierter Websitebuilder mit einer Vielzahl von Templates. Webflow eignet sich insbesondere für Leute, die bereits etwas Website-Erfahrung haben, da sich viele Konzepte aus der Programmierung von Websiten auch im visuellen Webflow-Editor wiederfinden. Webflow erlaubt den Export der erstellten Seite als Code und bietet zudem zahlreiche Lernressourcen zum Einstieg (Webflow <a href="https://webflow.com/community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Community</a>, Webflow <a href="https://university.webflow.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University</a>).</p>
<p class="msg msg--success">Pros: Mächtiger Editor, der auch komplexere Designs ermöglicht, viele Templates</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning">Cons: für simple Landing-Pages Overkill, entsprechend höheres Pricing</p>
<hr>
<div>The choice of a suitable website builder ultimately depends on your own requirements, the following questions should be answered for yourself:</div>
<ul>
<li>What budget do I have available?</li>
<li>How much experience do I have with the implementation of websites?</li>
<li>How much value do I place on ready-made templates?</li>
<li>Do I want to be able to remodel or even move my site, or do I throw it away in an emergency and start over again?</li>
</ul>
<div><hr></div>
<div>Are you interested in launching your own website and have questions or need support? We at Precelerator, the new service for tinkerers, coders and future entrepreneurs at SCE, will help you to get your project on the right track!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Send us a message over to <a href="mailto:precelerator@sce.de">precelerator@sce.de</a> and we'll get back to you as soon as possible.</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Design-Tool Figma: Gemeinsam klickbare Prototypen erstellen</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/design-tool-figma-klickbare-prototypen-in-kollaborativer-umgebung-erstellen.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/design-tool-figma-klickbare-prototypen-in-kollaborativer-umgebung-erstellen.html</id>
            <category term="Tools"/>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:32:01+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/Figma.png" alt="" />
                    Traditionally, there is a gap between the design and development of applications and websites: while designers often use image editing software such as Photoshop to provide static layouts and design templates, developers usually work with clickable and interactive prototypes. To bridge this gap, a variety of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/Figma.png" alt="" />
                <div>Traditionally, there is a gap between the design and development of applications and websites: while designers often use image editing software such as Photoshop to provide static layouts and design templates, developers usually work with clickable and interactive prototypes.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>To bridge this gap, a variety of advanced design tools have emerged in recent years to make the design process more interactive, collaborative and closer to the development process. Top performers in this area are <a href="https://www.sketch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Sketch</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> (OS X), </span><a href="https://www.adobe.com/de/products/xd.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Adobe Xd</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> (MacOS/ Windows) and the web-based tool </span><a href="https://www.figma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Figma</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> that this blog post is gonna dive in deeper into.</span></div>
<h4>What is Figma?</h4>
<blockquote>
<p>Figma helps teams create, test, and ship better designs from start to finish.</p>
</blockquote>
<div>Figma is a relatively young company in the design tools market and has a mission to rethink design and make it more accessible to designers and developers. The low barriers to entry (free for home users, web-based, easy to create and share prototypes) make Figma ideal for projects of all types involving the design of digital applications (apps, websites, etc.). Figma eliminates the need for traditional mockup/wireframe tools by quickly creating realistic interfaces with a visual editor that look very similar to "real" applications.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>To get a first impression of Figma's approach, it is worth taking a look at the following teaser (1:35):</div>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="640" height="360" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/365881491?color=5551ff" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></figure>
<h4>Figma: Getting Started</h4>
<p>In order to get started with Figma, head over to  <a href="https://www.figma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.figma.com/</a> and create your account. Since Figma is web based, you will be taken directly to the application, where after some setup questions a short introduction is waiting for you:</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/Figma-Intro.png" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-xs.png 300w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-sm.png 480w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-md.png 768w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-xl.png 1200w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-xxl.png 1600w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/4/responsive/Figma-Intro-xxxl.png 2560w"  alt="Figma Intro" width="554" height="322"></figure>
<p>If you prefer to work with the desktop app, you can find it in the web app via the menu -&gt; "Download desktop app". For inspiration, it is worthwhile to have a look at the example projects found in the "Recent" tab of the desktop app in the menu ("Prototyping in Figma", "Figma Basics", "Wireframing in Figma").</p>
<h4>Features</h4>
<div>Even in Free Plan, Figma allows you to invite project members to join projects and collaborate with them. A key feature of Figma is the ability to work together on a design project, regardless of the operating system. This allows all stakeholders to edit and comment on the project in order to develop a design together.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Created designs can be made available to others as a clickable prototype via the "Share" feature and can be tried out via a shareable link or even mobile via the "Figma Mirror" app.</div>
<p><span style="color: var(--headings-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: calc(1.125em + 0.14063 * ((100vw - 49rem) / 51)); font-weight: var(--font-weight-bold); letter-spacing: -0.03rem;">Tips &amp; Tricks</span></p>
<p>Design tools often have a certain learning curve due to their many different areas of application, but in Figma, this is limited to the minimum. The following key combinations and tips for using Figma are essential for getting started:</p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Scroll (mouse)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">Scroll up/down</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Ctrl+ Scrollen (Maus)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">Zoom in/out (zooms towards where the mouse hovers)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Space+ Drage (mouse)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">move view</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Shift + Click (mouse)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">highlight several elements at once</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Shift + Drag (mouse)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">Resize element without changing the side ratios</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Alt + Drag (mouse)</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">duplicate element</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Ctrl + G</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">Group elements so they can be dragged&amp;dropped together</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>For a quick start, we also recommend a look at the Figma Community-Section, where Figma users can obtain ready-made wireframes, templates, picture sets and icons. Especially for Figma beginners, you can find some quickstart templates here, which can also be used as inspiration for your own projects.</p>
<p>&lt;Überleitung zu Framer&gt;</p>
<h4>Resume</h4>
<p>Figma impresses with a generous free plan, collaboration possibilities for teams, demonstrability through divisible links and a very active community that provides sample resources and tutorials on a large scale.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>No-Code Tool Glide: Generate mobile-friendly apps from Google Sheets</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/no-code-tool-glide-mobilfaehige-apps-aus-google-sheets-generieren.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/no-code-tool-glide-mobilfaehige-apps-aus-google-sheets-generieren.html</id>
            <category term="Tools"/>
            <category term="Review"/>
            <category term="No-Code"/>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:41:31+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/3/glide.png" alt="" />
                    Spreadsheet software such as Excel and Google Sheets are an essential basis for data collection in a large number of projects, but they are often not clearly arranged and often unusable for mobile use. At the same time, spreadsheets are the most common source of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/3/glide.png" alt="" />
                <div>Spreadsheet software such as Excel and Google Sheets are an essential basis for data collection in a large number of projects, but they are often not clearly arranged and often unusable for mobile use. At the same time, spreadsheets are the most common source of data in all kinds of imaginable projects, which is a source of frequent annoyance.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>This is exactly the use case that the American startup Glide addresses and promises an automatic generation of mobile-capable web apps from Google Sheets. Programming knowledge is not necessary, everything you need is provided by Glide, which can be clicked together and even provides an extensive<span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><a href="https://www.glideapps.com/templates">template gallery</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> already, which contains demo apps for different use cases (e.g. a conference timetable, a CRM or a task tracker).</span></div>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technical Implementation<br><br></span></h4>
<div>Glide uses Google Sheets to store the app's data and generates a so-called progressive web app for the user, ultimately nothing more than a mobile web application that smartphone users can install on their home screen. This saves Glide the detour via the respective App Stores, instead a URL can be generated, via which users can use or install the created app. Due to the availability via a web link and the execution in the browser, Glide apps run automatically on any mobile device regardless of the operating system (whether Android, iOS, etc.). After clicking on the respective link, the user is prompted to add the app to the home screen of his smartphone. The trick: since Progressive Web Apps are web applications, the app does not cost any storage space, since unlike native apps, it runs directly in the user's browser.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>A visual editor allows Glide users to customize the look and feel of the app, so that the display and positioning of content can be adjusted as desired. Data can be adjusted in the associated spreadsheet, so that adding, editing and deleting entries can be done as usual within Google Sheets.</div>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pricing</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Glide offers different </span><a href="https://www.glideapps.com/pricing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pricing-Plans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the Personal Plan with Glide logo and some restrictions (&lt;500 records, &lt;1000 edits per month, &lt;100 MB storage space for pictures etc.) is provided free of charge. Professional apps without branding and with additional features such as upstream authentication, a dedicated domain, up to 25000 records, 10 GB of memory and unlimited edits are available for around 30€ per month.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Resume</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, Glide provides an impressive feature set for no-code apps, and with Google Sheets data storage and visual app editor, it is especially suited for users who have no programming experience. Due to the technical implementation as a progressive web app, Glide apps are very easy to divide and install, so that a presentable application can be created with just a few hours of work. Due to the Glide branding, the free plan is only suitable for more professional projects to a limited extent, but with 30€ per month, the pricing for pro apps is extremely low compared to self-implementation or commissioning an app development. Glide positions itself prominently in the area of simple list-based apps, but with features such as the display of content such as images or maps, it also offers content that goes beyond pure lists. Depending on the application, it depends on whether Glide is a sensible choice, so it is worth taking a look at the </span><a href="https://www.glideapps.com/templates">sample applications</a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in order to get a better feeling for the features and limitations of Glide.</span></p>
<hr>
<h3>Call To Action</h3>
<div>Are you interested in launching your own project and have questions or need support? We at Precelerator, the new offer for tinkerers, coders and future entrepreneurs at SCE, will help you to get your project on the right track!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Send us a message over to <a href="mailto:precelerator@sce.de">precelerator@sce.de</a> and we'll get back to you as soon as we can.</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title> No-Code Tool Bubble: Visually create web apps</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/no-code-tool-bubble-web-apps-erstellen.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/no-code-tool-bubble-web-apps-erstellen.html</id>
            <category term="Tools"/>
            <category term="Review"/>
            <category term="No-Code"/>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:40:52+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/2/bubble.png" alt="" />
                    Whether TripAdvisor, AirBnB or Shopify: Web apps and platforms represent the most important platform for consumer and B2B applications alongside mobile apps. Until a few years ago, this area was still dependent on complex web development, but more and more so-called no- or low-code platforms&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/2/bubble.png" alt="" />
                <p>Whether TripAdvisor, AirBnB or Shopify: Web apps and platforms represent the most important platform for consumer and B2B applications alongside mobile apps. Until a few years ago, this area was still dependent on complex web development, but more and more so-called no- or low-code platforms are emerging, which allow even less technically skilled users to create web applications.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the no-code platforms is <a href="https://bubble.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bubble</a>, a young start-up from New York. The platform promises to simplify the creation of fully functional web applications using the company's own visual programming language. Web applications created using Bubble are hosted by Bubble itself and are accessible to users via URL.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Features</span></h4>
<p>Bubble offers various features such as authentication (an upstream logon/registration), storage, retrieval and processing of data, connection of APIs, i.e. interfaces to any backend, and the connection of payment providers (e.g. Stripe). Created web applications can be built responsive, i.e. suitable for all screen sizes, so that they can also be displayed appropriately on smartphones and tablets.</p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Principles of Bubble</span></h4>
<p>The user interface of bubble applications can be assembled from a library of interface components (buttons, text fields, etc.) by drag and drop. So-called workflows regulate the processes that should be executed by the application during user interactions. </p>
<h4>Learn how to use Bubble</h4>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Introduction and documentation</td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="https://manual.bubble.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://manual.bubble.io/</span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interactive Lessons</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="https://bubble.io/lessons"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://bubble.io/lessons</span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Advanced Lessons in order to imitate popular web apps</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="https://bubble.io/how-to-build"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://bubble.io/how-to-build</span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assistance/ Community</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="https://forum.bubble.io/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://forum.bubble.io/</span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketplace for templates and plugins</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><a href="https://bubble.io/marketplace"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://bubble.io/marketplace</span></a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Showcase gallery for inspirations</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://bubble.io/showcase">https://bubble.io/showcase</a></span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pricing</span></h4>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Free Plan with branding, no own domain</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">free</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">25$/month</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Professional</span></td>
<td style="width: 50%;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">115$/month</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>More information in regards to pricing over at <a href="https://bubble.io/pricing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">https://bubble.io/pricing</span></a></p>
<h4>Review - Bubble, the right platform for your MVP?</h4>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4W-LENVu8uc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<h4>In-depth Guide for Bubble</h4>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6OKVj1A9OcY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<hr>
<h3>Call To Action</h3>
<div>You are interested in launching your own project and have questions or need support? We at Precelerator, the new offer for tinkerers, coders and future entrepreneurs at SCE, will help you to get your project on the right track!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Send us a mail to <a href="mailto:precelerator@sce.de">precelerator@sce.de</a> and we will get back to you as soon as we can.</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Recommended (Online-) Ressourcen for your side projects</title>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Maienschein</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/empfohlene-ressourcen.html"/>
        <id>https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/empfohlene-ressourcen.html</id>
            <category term="Tools"/>
            <category term="Project"/>
            <category term="Code"/>

        <updated>2020-10-07T21:47:13+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/garrhet-sampson-CmF_5GYc6c0-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                    Students, as future workers and decision makers, are an ideal target group for software tool vendors, so many vendors have started to provide generous free trial or free plans to convince them of the quality of these offerings. Such resources are ideal for smaller projects&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/garrhet-sampson-CmF_5GYc6c0-unsplash.jpg" alt="" />
                <div>Students, as future workers and decision makers, are an ideal target group for software tool vendors, so many vendors have started to provide generous free trial or free plans to convince them of the quality of these offerings. Such resources are ideal for smaller projects to build on and gain experience with these technologies. In this lesson you will learn about various offerings and resources that you can use for your next side project!</div>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">1) Free tools for design and development</span></h4>
<p>The following free tools are especially popular within designers and developers:</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">Visual Studio Code</a><span style="color: var(--text-editor-body-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">: The open source code editor from Microsoft, which is a general-purpose weapon for development projects due to its simple, but powerful user interface and can be adapted almost arbitrarily by means of Plugins.</span></p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://www.figma.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Figma</a>: A modern application design tool that allows the design of user interface mockups and provides clickable prototypes via a link. Figma also emphasizes collaborative features that facilitate a common design and review process.</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://git-scm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Git</a>: Git hat sich in den letzten Jahren das populärste Tool zur Versionierung und Quellcodeverwaltung durchgesetzt und ist für alle Coding-Projekte grundlegend. Gehostete Quellcodeverwaltung wie <a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub </a>und <a href="https://about.gitlab.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitLab </a>ermöglicht es, Source Code öffentlich (oder privat) abzulegen, und direkt auch zu hosten (<a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Pages</a>) oder als Grundlage für Continuous Integration/ Continuous Deployment (<a href="https://github.com/features/actions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Actions</a>).<br>Die Hochschule München bietet außerdem eine eigengehostete <a href="https://gitlab.lrz.de/users/sign_in" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitLab-Instanz</a>, die allen Angehörigen der Hochschule mihilfe ihrer Hochschulkennung offensteht.</p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">2) Free offers for hosting and cloud infrastructure</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The following providers are particularly recommended due to their generous free plans for hosting smaller projects and websites:<br></span></p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/de/education/awseducate/students/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Educate</a> - Student access to Amazon's cloud services with $100 starting credit (no credit card required)</p>
<div>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://www.netlify.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Netlify </a>- extremely simple deployments of front-end resources (websites and applications) directly from the source code management or alternatively via drag &amp; drop of local files</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://firebase.google.com/?hl=de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Firebase </a>- Backend-as-a-Service service from Google that provides free quotas for services such as authentication, hosting and storage (Firestore).</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://www.heroku.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Heroku </a>- Hosting of web applications (free plan with restrictions, option of a free hobby dyno via GitHub Student)</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amazon Webservices</a>, <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/de-de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Azure</a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/?hl=de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Cloud Platform</a> - even the large business clouds offer free plans, often without a credit card (e.g. <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/de-de/free/students/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Azure Student</a>).</p>
</div>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">3) GitHub Student Developer Pack</span></h4>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602.png" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" srcset="https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-xs.png 300w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-sm.png 480w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-md.png 768w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-xl.png 1200w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-xxl.png 1600w ,https://precelerator.github.io/blog-en/media/posts/1/responsive/Screenshot-2020-09-18-122602-xxxl.png 2560w"  alt="GitHub Student Developer Pack"></figure>
<div>
<div>Probably the largest collection of free software resources, the GitHub Student Developer Pack deserves a mention in any such list. Students with valid university addresses will receive a variety of offers after verification by GitHub. These include free domains (.me and .tech, limited to 1 year), cloud resources (AWS, Azure, Heroku), a cooperation with <a href="https://unity.com/de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Unity </a>(free assets), professional development environments for a variety of programming languages (<a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/de-de/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jetbrains) </a>sas well as one to six month accesses for Tech course platforms (<a href="https://frontendmasters.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FrontendMasters</a>, <a href="https://onemonth.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">One Month</a>, <a href="https://flatironschool.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flatiron School</a>).</div>
<div> </div>
<div>A complete overview of all included freebies can be found <a href="https://education.github.com/pack" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, also it's worth taking a look into the <a href="https://education.github.com/pack/gallery?filter=All&amp;sort=newest&amp;tag=All" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gallery of projects built with resources from the GitHub Student Pack</a>.</div>
<hr>
<h3>Call To Action</h3>
<div>You are interested in launching your own project and have questions or need support? We at Precelerator, the new offer for tinkerers, coders and future entrepreneurs at SCE, will help you to get your project on the right track!</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Send us a mail to <a href="mailto:precelerator@sce.de">precelerator@sce.de</a> and we'll get back to you as soon as we can.</div>
</div>
<div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
